There may be occasions where you need
to send documents out to customers or
clients where they need to indicate
a preference for a specific item
or there maybe multiple choice.
To do this, within Word you have the
developer tab where you can create
check boxes or drop down lists.
In this video, I'm going to demonstrate
how you can add check boxes and drop
down lists to a preformatted template.
You can download these templates from
the page on the vision2learn website.
So the first thing I need to do is I
have my template open on the screen
and I'm going to add some check boxes
alongside each of these options.
The first thing I need to do is to
make sure that my cursor is placed
at the point where I want to insert
the drop-down list or check boxes.
So I've moved along there.
I'm going to use the tab key just
to move it along one further,
one space further, and then I'm
going to go to the developer tab.
And when I'm on the developer
tab, there are a range of options.
Now, the tools that we're looking
for is in the controls section.
So if I click on the checkbox content
control and click that, it will
insert a checkbox where the cursor is.
I then need to duplicate that,
for the next checkbox, and again,
use the tab key to line them up.
Place my cursor there, press the
tab key till they're lined up.
Down to the next option.
Use the tab  key to line them up.
And finally add the last checkbox.
Now these boxes should work straight away.
So you should be able to
check or uncheck these boxes.
So a customer could then
indicate their preferences.
However, the document hasn't been
protected, so customers or anyone
can actually edit the document.
Which isn't recommended.
So what we need to do to avoid that
is to actually protect the document.
So if you look along the toolbar, you
can see the restrict, editing icon.
And if I click on that, it brings up a
range of options on the right hand pane.
So what I want to do is I
want to restrict the editing.
So.,yes, it is filling in forms.
So we want to allow customers,
or clients to fill in forms.
So that's correct.
And then select yes, start
enforcing protection.
So once I've clicked that it'll
ask me for a password and I will
just enter a password, click OK.
So now when I come to edit the document, I
can check or uncheck the boxes but I will
not be able to edit or make any changes.
No matter what I try.
I can't highlight anything.
The only editable options within
the document are the check boxes.
Now that you've learned how to create
check boxes, I'm going to demonstrate
how you can insert drop down lists.
As you can see, I'm using a very similar
template to the one used previously,
the only difference being is that the
number of options have been reduced.
The reason for this is that the drop
down list will contain the numbers of
people who may be interested, which
the reader can then select from.
So the first thing you need to do is
to make sure that I'm on the developer
tab and make sure my cursor's in the
position where I wish the dropdown
is to be placed use the tab key
for that, just to move it further
along a little bit, and reduce that.
And then from the controls bar,
I will then select a drop down
list, content control that will
insert that first drop down list.
I then need to do the same for
the next two dropdown lists.
And that has inserted the three
dropdown lists as required.
Now  that that drop down
list has been inserted.
I need to populate them because as you
see, if I click on them, there's only
one option in there, which is choose
an item which is placed in by default.
So to do that, I'll click
on the first drop down list.
And then I need to go up to the top and
select properties, the control properties,
and that will open up the dialog box where
I can make changes to the dropdown list.
The first thing I need
to do is give it a title.
So I will type in there
"People who are interested".
Now the next thing is that I need
to add some options to the dropdown.
So the first thing to do is click add.
I'm going to insert the
number one, add again.
Add in the number two.
Add again and the number three.
Add again, the number four and
finally once more add and the
number five and plus, click OK.
So once I've done that, I can click
OK and that will then have populated
the dropdown list with the options
to select from one to five plus.
I then need to duplicate that for
the following two dropdown boxes.
So again, select the second box,
select properties, give it the title.
Click add.
One, two, three, four, five plus.
Click OK.
And finally for the third dropdown,
select the properties, give it the
title and then add the numbers.
Once that has been done, click OK.
So I now have all three
drop down lists populated.
As we can see they all work and people
who are reading the document can
make selections from the dropdowns.
As with the checkbox document,
people can still edit this.
So again, what you would need to do
is to protect the document and click
on the restrict editing button, make
sure that it is set to allow only
this type of editing in the document,
which is filling in forms, and then
select yes, start enforcing protection.
Add a password.
Click OK.
And that document is now protected.
While people can make changes from
the dropdown, nobody can make any
changes to the rest of the document.